Joshua Yi

Software Engineer

Personal Info

Address

5 Saddle Hill Lane

Ashland, MA

E-mail

jyi468@gmail.com

GitHub

https://github.com/jyi468

LinkedIn

www.linkedin.com/in/joshua-yi-94996151

Skills

Python

AngularJS, Javascript, HTML, CSS

ReactJS, Java, Spring

C++, C#, R, ASP.Net MVC

Languages

English

Korean

Software engineer with 5+ years of experience and strong analytic background from Physics.

Experience with Biophysics research, domain knowledge and software.

Interest in working with Python, Machine Learning and data.

Outgoing, creative and detail-oriented. Focused on finding efficient solutions and constant improvement, in and out of work.

Experience

Feb 2015 - **Software Engineer**

present

Amadeus IT Group

- Built the Hotel Application Portal, a content management system designed to handle data for roughly 10,000 hotels worldwide
- Developed UI components in AngularJS and Javascript
- Integrated Server-side components using Spring MVC and Java
- Performance analysis and refactoring to help system handle over 50,000 transactions per second
- Architected and designed various application features for use by hoteliers and corporate level staff.
- Utilized Agile methodologies and technologies such as Scrum and Kanban for project management.

Jun 2014 -Feb 2015

Application Developer

Eliza Corporation

- Developed speech recognition applications using Javascript for automating health care interactions
- Managed grammars and lexicons necessary for language processing
- Customized user interaction call scripts depending on clients' needs
- Utilized Eliza Cloud software to deploy applications to testing and production environments
- Interacted with database containing millions of records of customer data

May 2012 -Sep 2012

Particle Physics Research Assistant

5 2012 Kumar Lab

- Simulated particle collisions and designed detector geometries using GEANT4 (a C++ framework)
- Utilized ROOT to script various test cases (protons, electrons, differing energies, etc.) for GEANT4 simulations
- Operated, developed and scripted in Linux environment (Ubuntu)

Dec 2010 -Sep 2011

Biophysics Research Assistant

Kilfoil Lab

- Created and used existing MATLAB image processing and machine learning algorithms to achieve sub-pixel resolution on microscopic images
- Investigated physical properties of cellular fibers and cytoskeleton using physics formulae and MATLAB functional programming
- Analyzed statistical and physical data using MATLAB Statistics Toolbox

Education

Sep 2008 - University of Massachusetts Amherst

May 2012

• B.S. in Physics

Aug 2018 - Georgia Institute of Technology

• Ongoing M.S. in Computer Science with a specialization in Machine Learning